<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-22T22:02:20-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Archive #2</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Square</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/square.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Square" /><published>2020-09-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/square</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/square.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-09-22.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;all the other sketches are as wonky as the top half and not as &lt;em&gt;ooh&lt;/em&gt; as the bottom half; that’s why this one is pictured&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading in square pics for a square brush. I understand this brush shape, whereas pointed brushes and pens continue to merely be an inking-in-outlines tools for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;+ &lt;em&gt;nepantla&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nepantla&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; / learned about through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MWVUEJSh7bo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;May-Li Khoe&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vut--TS7FoQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Federico Ardila&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
+ &lt;em&gt;nakasi&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nakasi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://beingwendyhsu.info/?page_id=1194&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; / learned through the band &lt;a href=&quot;https://wepresent.wetransfer.com/story/mong-tong/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mong Tong&lt;/a&gt; (one of the members collects &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/homyu_books/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Taiwanese sci-fi book covers&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a month of work and less so words. In my drafts from earlier this month are &lt;em&gt;nepantla&lt;/em&gt; (in-between-ness), &lt;em&gt;nakasi&lt;/em&gt; (in Taiwanese and Japanese cultures, parlor/bar-accompaniment-music associated with the working class), and thoughts about supremacist perfection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are taught perfection.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before design school, one often doesn’t see all the little so-called imperfections. And then you learn how to judge all those details, what’s “right” and “wrong.” What wasn’t distracting before is suddenly an itch. And guess who cares and is aware about those details: not most people. Do we talk about language and communication enough? Formal aspects are easier to talk about, quicker to point out. And then when looking at other people’s work, it becomes easy to dismiss it as unprofessional if a non-crucial detail is a little off. And not just to dismiss&lt;/em&gt; it&lt;em&gt;, but also&lt;/em&gt; the person &lt;em&gt;behind it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perfection isn’t the point.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of sentiments about freeing oneself and others from perfection. Unpacking what that actionably and perceptively means is subjective. Do I believe in the rules and personally unlived truths I’ve absorbed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p.s. the new album &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tqVxd57H-cA&amp;amp;list=PLfsbuQF4YPohXa4nvblxJQX-_ptryBAle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shore&lt;/em&gt; by Fleet Foxes&lt;/a&gt; is lovely.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="September 2020" /><summary type="html">all the other sketches are as wonky as the top half and not as ooh as the bottom half; that’s why this one is pictured</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bro de Does</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/systematically-sloppy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bro de Does" /><published>2020-08-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/systematically-sloppy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/systematically-sloppy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-21.png#small&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;from the hit documentary &lt;em&gt;Systematically Sloppy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">from the hit documentary Systematically Sloppy</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beyond representation&amp;amp;colon; relationality &amp;amp; the plurastic self</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/20/beyond-representation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beyond representation&amp;colon; relationality &amp; the plurastic self" /><published>2020-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/20/beyond-representation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/20/beyond-representation.html">&lt;p&gt;Quotes from “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-flux.com/journal/106/314167/can-we-share-a-world-beyond-representation/&quot;&gt;Can We Share a World Beyond Representation?&lt;/a&gt;” (February 2020) by Irmgard Emmelhainz, who argues for doing away with “representation, recognition, and difference and replace them with frames for relationality and reciprocity”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rootlessness, violence, the shattering and loss of all traditions, loneliness, mental decay, and illness—this is the inheritance from modernity in the West and in Westernized territories throughout the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Modernity also means the replacement of “society” and “community” by “mass society.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of these quotes from &lt;em&gt;The Darker Side of Western Modernity&lt;/em&gt; by Walter Mignolo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The subject of theological knowledge depended on the dictates of God, while the subject of secular philosophy/science depended on Reason, on the Cartesian ego/mind and Kant’s transcendental reason. Thus, Western imperial knowledge, cast in Western imperial languages, was theo-politically and ego-politically founded.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;geo- and body-politics of knowledge, decolonial thinking and the decolonial option, place human lives and life in general first, rather than advocating for the “transformation of the disciplines.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the absence of body- and geo-politics in Western thinking — removal of body and place — is wholly colonial, the very definition of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Emmelhainz article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In their rebellion, avant-garde artists made a tactical, temporary, local, contrived, problematic, and idealistic alliance with the working class and the marginalized… This attempted alliance was based on &lt;em&gt;representativity&lt;/em&gt;: an invisible social contract in which artists imagined themselves to be mandated by humanity to address humanity in the name of universal values, grounded in a conflict between the individual (artist) and societal structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could representation (potential homogenization, nonconsensual agency) be as deceitful as inclusion and diversity (i.e. assimilation and tokenism) which was preceded by desegregation (i.e. assimilation)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Cue intersectionality.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been by moral struggle with understanding the marginalized groups that I am part of, but not feeling like I represent anyone other than myself. And I think again of being in the middle space: of being marginalized but then afforded privileged opportunities &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; I am part of marginalized groups. Can I only profit from my own oppression? I think of the artists, etc. who were given voice, attention, finally, but because someone in the group they represent died unjustly or was belittled by the very industry that now has felt pressured to give voice to ___ artist. How can I trust that I do represent, without knowing how much I have actually assimilated by accepting opportunities? But how else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also cannot say I am represented by a group or a person, but groups and persons, and even then parts of groups and persons, which really means parts of everyone and peoples. I bring up a question I’ve asked before: am I a synthesis of everyone or a refinement of myself? The fallacy in this question is the “or” dichotomy. We may be individuals, but we are pluralistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each user/citizen/consumer, the digital neoliberal capitalist order offers an individualized, tailor-made reality. This process occurs and repeats to the point that our “normal” now consists of living in a world in which we all have the right to retreat to our own private worlds of meaning, tailored by the algorithms of digital interfaces that constantly adapt to each user’s individual needs. The possibility of a world in common has been replaced by myriad niches for the private consumption of digitalized content. Clearly, representation—the &lt;em&gt;dispositif&lt;/em&gt; that, via speech and action, enables appearance in the world in common, and also the human capacity for the creation and dissemination of shared meaning and traditions—has been hijacked by capitalism, authoritarianism, democracy, the internet, and spectacle. (Emmelhainz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do we share more often than the architectures that contain us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Artists replaced the invisible social contract from early modernity that had enabled them to speak on behalf of all of humanity with a new one, in which they spoke from the point of view of their own gender, ethnic origin, political struggle, or sexual orientation, as colonized peoples, minorities, workers, etc. … A new, invisible social contract was drawn up in which individuals would now only speak on behalf of themselves as representatives of their own personal experiences of ethnic, political, or gendered specificities, with the mandate to address “everyone” and to secure recognition of “my” ordeal. Equality came to mean equal access to visibility through self-representation.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Under globalization, art is disseminated to a globalized mass society through an internationalized culture industry. Governments and corporations monopolize this culture industry for the purpose of managing the dissent and antagonism produced by the neoliberal order. In other words, states and corporations instrumentalize art as a showcase for global democracy; they point to art that expresses dissent as proof of how “democratic” and “tolerant” the neoliberal order is. (Emmelhainz)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representatives (individuals) part of marginalized groups are seen as a success for the advancement of those groups. But a representative is not the group itself. But we must start and inspire somewhere. But is the start to that answer through an individual breakthrough, or as Emmelhainz concludes, through mutual aid and reciprocity? Breaking through together, not individually through the helping hand of the privileged. But how can you under such grand systems that constantly erode the sustainability of any alternative? One of the greatest struggles is having enough money and resources. And guess who holds the money and resources? AH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how do you respond without violence, the requirement in past revolutions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;communities of morally concerned spectators&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Irmgard Emmelhainz&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The codependent politics of appearance demands a form of &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;despotic empathy&lt;/span&gt; generated by situating oneself, or others on whose behalf one speaks, in the place of the martyr or scapegoat seeking recognition and visibility. Furthermore, the modern practice of “looking at the pain of others” has created a form of “reified subjectivity” that enables a spectacularized, uncommitted, and “post-political” position vis-à-vis the world. This means that from the perspective of reified subjectivity, as Anita Chari argues, the economy exists as a domain that is separate from human activity, blinding the subject to the extent of her involvement in the capitalist processes in which we are all complicit. As a pathology, reified subjectivity leaves room only for despotic empathy, which in turn forecloses the possibility of seeing actual power relations that divide the world between “the wretched of the screen” and spectators living in privileged enclaves with access to cultural commodities. (Emmelhainz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emmelhainz ends with an appropriately nebulous proposal of relationality and reciprocity. Relationality makes sense to me more so than representation. It implies a horizontality that is missing in representation, which connotes a singular face speaking for a faceless mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-flux.com/journal/106/314167/can-we-share-a-world-beyond-representation/&quot;&gt;read the entire article&lt;/a&gt; which I have basically quoted half of here. It’s not that long yet says so much. I understand it, but am still trying to understand it. The context of decolonial readings like Freire’s &lt;em&gt;Pedagogy of the Oppressed&lt;/em&gt; and introduction to Fanon’s &lt;em&gt;Wretched of the Earth&lt;/em&gt; helps informs and contextualizes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">Quotes from “Can We Share a World Beyond Representation?” (February 2020) by Irmgard Emmelhainz, who argues for doing away with “representation, recognition, and difference and replace them with frames for relationality and reciprocity”:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“::”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/18/parallels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“::”" /><published>2020-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/18/parallels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/18/parallels.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nail salon :: graphic design&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
creative labor largely in service of the rich white corporate (but who isn’t under service of rich white corporations)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christianity :: white supremacist patriarchy&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
saviorism, worshipping individuals, a virgin giving birth, martyrdom, chants, prewritten prayers &lt;br /&gt;
living in a matriarchal household under a patriarchal society isn’t great either&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;design :: competition&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Modes of Criticism articles: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://modesofcriticism.org/graphic-design-systems/&quot;&gt;Graphic Design Systems&lt;/a&gt;” &amp;amp; “&lt;a href=&quot;https://modesofcriticism.org/its-nice-that-intro/&quot;&gt;It’s Nice That Intro&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;br /&gt;
hierarchies, standing out, grabbing attention, networking, awards, self-commodification &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American &lt;del&gt;dream&lt;/del&gt; myth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There’s so much error in language &lt;br /&gt;
Everything we say turns out not right &lt;br /&gt;
Or almost right; that is, to be precise, wrong &lt;br /&gt;
So we left language, but there was nowhere to go so we &lt;br /&gt;
came back&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;from &lt;em&gt;The Pirate Who Does Not Know the Value of Pi&lt;/em&gt;, Eugene Ostashevsky&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The partial poem above starts off the article “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.e-flux.com/journal/103/286824/sleep-walks-the-street-part-1/&quot;&gt;Sleep Walks the Street, Part I&lt;/a&gt;” by Metahaven, who argue that “metaphors, metonyms, and allegories have become scalable political technologies obfuscating, undermining, and instrumentalizing the realities they represent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Platforms such as Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube are all explicitly associated and involved with processes of political and ideological cognitive short circuiting—for example, through disinformation campaigns, hyper-targeted ads, trolls and bots, algorithmic suggestion and autoplay, as well as resultant “filter bubbles.” As such, they act as interfacial windows in which that which is visible passes for “the world.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a reminder that the internet has long been a dimensional layer to world, not separate from it. For some, Facebook is their entire internet. We are still catching up to media literacy. The speed of everything is inhuman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I viewed design often as visual metaphor. Design composition is a form of collage. Beautiful when poetic. Eventually gimmicky when clever. Insidious when deceitful. Somewhat inaccessible when innovative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metaphor is ingrained in how we think, speak, understand, make. Why do we find so much meaning in metaphor? Has its appropriation stained it? Can it be trusted?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do words speak louder than actions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raw emotion is indigestible. We often understand it through a medium, a material, a product. It has to be processed and sold. Is that evidence of inhumanity? Or is it a result of emotion’s potency?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storytelling and language feel essential to being a human though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So often in design and art, metaphor is another layer to interpret. It complicates the process. What and how does it mean to be straightforward? Why has Trump’s language angered the progressives while illuminating rural white America and conservative immigrants? Do we truly listen to those who do not speak like us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers are agents of culture. And what is culture under a patriarchal capitalist white supremacy?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">nail salon :: graphic design creative labor largely in service of the rich white corporate (but who isn’t under service of rich white corporations)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lettering as journaling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/lettering-as-journaling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lettering as journaling" /><published>2020-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/lettering-as-journaling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/16/lettering-as-journaling.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-16a.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;from 11.19.2019&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lettering sketches are a synchronization of thinking and drawing. The words come as I draw/write them. It’s a slowed down version of journaling, forcing me to be succinct. It reveals the primary worries, or sometimes non-worries. It allows me to come to words in a present way that is not as immediate as speaking (which I am not good at).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When nothing anxious is on my mind, the pages end up being random layered chaos as I try to search for something:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-16b.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;from 11.14.2019&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-16c.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;from 10.30.2019&lt;/h6&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">from 11.19.2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Changeling” by Hieu Minh Nguyen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/15/hieu-minh-nguyen-changeling-template.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Changeling” by Hieu Minh Nguyen" /><published>2020-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/15/hieu-minh-nguyen-changeling-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/15/hieu-minh-nguyen-changeling-template.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-15.jpeg#small&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;by Hieu Minh Nguyen, a poet around my age who is from Minnesota (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KelliAgodon/status/1290103348935327744/photo/1&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I typed the poem, but realized that a lot of poems aren’t made for web typography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is eerie how poems and prose I’ve written in the past hold similar themes and metaphors to “Changeling”. I regret not attending one of Paul Tran’s poetry workshops, as we were both students at WashU. My friend attended and loved it. Paul started off the workshop asking what everyone’s rose, thorn, and bud was that day. I don’t know why the Vietnamese Students Association never reached out to them. Man is it cool as heck to keep learning about these Vietnamese poets instead of hearing from my mom about another faceless cousin  becoming a doctor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">by Hieu Minh Nguyen, a poet around my age who is from Minnesota (source)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lyotard tailspin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/14/lyotard-tailspin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lyotard tailspin" /><published>2020-08-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/14/lyotard-tailspin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/14/lyotard-tailspin.html">&lt;p&gt;First semester junior year, second semester of being in the design major, I was thrown into an existential and philosophical tailspin (which I didn’t realize that’s what it was until later, though I remember my professor Ben, who was frustrated at my struggle, asking me if I was having an existential crisis) in trying to make an editorial book containing “The Crystal Goblet” (the required text) by Beatrice Warde and “Paradox on the Graphic Artist” (my chosen text) by Jean-François Lyotard. When I struggled before, it was no big deal. I moved on and improved, in bliss of being in design school, but thinking in the back of head, &lt;em&gt;when will I be jaded by all of this?&lt;/em&gt;. Pretty soon apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this struggle was less about skill and more about deep critical thinking about design and my place in it. And because I was not prolifically producing and iterating, the project felt like a failure, even though it was not a bad book. There seems to not be room for theory in undergrad, or I just didn’t have anyone to talk to about it. In any case the thinking was crucial to what was to come, and I regret nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason I thought back to this time and a message I wrote that I wanted to print photocopies of and distribute on my peers’ desks anonymously. But I was too scared to do it. It probably would have been confusing and weird anyway. Manifestos are the language of patriarchal white supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;December 2017&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes that followed that writing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cool if you like it in the end, but I myself need to feel proud of what I’ve done. I’m over all the neat, well-done stuff because, well, I’m not learning that much anymore. I’m just doing what I already know. What an uninspiring way to live. I almost avoid confidence in pursuit of staying humble. There is so much I still don’t know.&lt;/em&gt; Endless solutions. &lt;em&gt;That’s the addiction of design: there is no single, definite solution like there is in math. So the solution, the perceived ending, can always be improved, which means there is always something to learn. But I guess I’m done learning all the little things that don’t significantly matter in the long run. A lot of those little things are in pursuit of perfection that that don’t really benefit anyone or anything. They’re kind of just a way of showing off how anal you are and how good you are at spotting little things. But what about the big things? Yeah, what you’ve made is nice and neat but&lt;/em&gt; what does it say? What can I learn from it? What questions does it raise? &lt;em&gt;What do I now see or know after looking/reading your design? That’s what I care about. I hate wasting my time on things that offer nothing. Especially those things that are parasitic or selfish. So that’s why I’m wary of ad agencies and the paradigm of the job search. Because the goal is for yourself to get a job, and that involves using other people to get there in a way. This artificiality is rubbing off on me. So is this why I isolate myself? Because I can feel myself becoming all like them? If we’re all the same, how the hell is this world going to change. It’s not being different for the sake of different but to offer another perspective, to expand the visible field of possibilities so that a better solution — always temporary and changeable — can be discovered. Then we can take what we’ve learned from that and continue onward.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed that I tend to forget what I’ve written as it becomes ingrained in my actions instead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">First semester junior year, second semester of being in the design major, I was thrown into an existential and philosophical tailspin (which I didn’t realize that’s what it was until later, though I remember my professor Ben, who was frustrated at my struggle, asking me if I was having an existential crisis) in trying to make an editorial book containing “The Crystal Goblet” (the required text) by Beatrice Warde and “Paradox on the Graphic Artist” (my chosen text) by Jean-François Lyotard. When I struggled before, it was no big deal. I moved on and improved, in bliss of being in design school, but thinking in the back of head, when will I be jaded by all of this?. Pretty soon apparently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paul Tran &amp;amp; Audre Lorde</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/13/paul-tran.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paul Tran &amp; Audre Lorde" /><published>2020-08-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/13/paul-tran</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/13/paul-tran.html">&lt;h4&gt;There’s an infinite past… And I come to poetry because I want to write the primary source documents for my mother and I.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Paul Tran (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poetryfoundation.org/podcasts/149312/vs-ep-31-paul-tran-vs-the-past&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Paul studied history and has found that poetry (an act of creation) is a way to address the present and expand the histories of Vietnamese Americans that white scholars and writers cannot.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before typography came language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of authorship and what centering history means, as much of it is displayed through individuals and individualized events, objects, etc. when truly we are all an accumulation. What is left unsaid, and therefore eventually forgotten? Yet, the now perpetually becomes the past. Past and future are extended. But why think of past, present, future separately when they exist all at once?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is incredibly powerful to be able to hear queer Vietnamese American creatives and thinkers. It has been hitting me to realize that only contemporaries exist for this perspective, as the Vietnam War ended only 45 years ago. I am part of the precedent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered why I had a hard time truly taking the advice of older people. Part of it is probably a tendency-to-not-listen-to-adults problem, but also they are fundamentally not me and I am not them. My brothers and I have always learned the hard way, i.e. by doing. It is still a mystery to me the what and how of getting help, when so often it is just a matter of getting me to do what I am thinking. Getting help is often getting validation or some form of permission. When will I entirely be autonomous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I am most autonomous when I make, as thinking and doing synchronize. Then critique and feedback and deadlines are structures for maintaining momentum more than anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still need to do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audre Lorde’s Questionnaire to Oneself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;What are the words you do not have yet? [&lt;em&gt;Or&lt;/em&gt;, “for what do you not have words, yet?”]&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;What do you need to say? [List as many things as necessary]&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;What are the tyrannies you swallow day by day and attempt to make your own, until you will sicken and die of them, still in silence? [List as many as necessary today. Then write a new list tomorrow. And the day after.]&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;If we have been socialized to respect fear more than our own need for language, ask yourself: “What’s the worst that could happen to me if I tell this truth?” [So, answer this today. And everyday.]&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking at these questions again and typing them out, I am realizing that I already am &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; a lot of these.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">There’s an infinite past… And I come to poetry because I want to write the primary source documents for my mother and I. Paul Tran (source). Paul studied history and has found that poetry (an act of creation) is a way to address the present and expand the histories of Vietnamese Americans that white scholars and writers cannot.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“The Fall” by Russell Edson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/12/decomposition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“The Fall” by Russell Edson" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/12/decomposition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/12/decomposition.html">&lt;p&gt;Ocean Vuong shared on his Instagram story one poem that changed his life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fall by Russell Edson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There was a man who found two leaves and came indoors holding them out saying to his parents that he was a tree.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;To which they said then go into the yard and do not grow in the living room as your roots may ruin the carpet.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;He said I was fooling I am not a tree and he dropped his leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;But his parents said look it is fall.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of my college admission essay which began with “My mom is trying to create a clone of her idealistic self.” My mother was always telling me to drink more milk so that I would grow taller and have stronger bones, a nagging advice that continued throughout high school. Then I elaborate on my disbelief of Catholicism and consequential performative &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_in_the_Catholic_Church&quot;&gt;confirmation&lt;/a&gt; to appease my unknowing parents. The first time I went to confession was to tell the priest that I was not Catholic. No one really knows how to react to the quiet kid who eventually speaks up to hyperventilate that they reject everything, how to respond to someone who is so vehemently and clearly saying no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my essay I see this experience as a rotting piece of my heart decomposing and become fertilizer for the self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking “Christ’s blood” didn’t teach me anything, but not drinking it did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never did drink the milk my mother poured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote the essay for a memoir prompt in an English class taught by Ryan Stripling, a very kind dude who sponsored the literary magazine crew and was one of those life-changing English teachers. He would write a letter to every one of his students at the end of year about how their presence contributed to the classroom, or how they grew, and encouraging how they can grow. He believed that “words create worlds.” I had intended to write a thank you letter after graduating college as I never did in high school. At the end of last year, I went to see what he was up to as I last heard he was writing a book. I found out he just died of cancer in a span of half a year. That was the first time that someone in my life died. I still am hesitant on rushing, but perhaps it is naïve to continue assuming that I have plenty of time. No one knows that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Tran is another contemporary Vietnamese American poet. A snippet from one of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogthisrock.blogspot.com/2018/03/split-this-rock-interview-with-paul-tran.html&quot;&gt;interviews&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I believe the poet should investigate. Investigation is important to me because our world, as every world before ours, needs thinkers to illuminate the human condition: why are we here and what does it mean for us to be here? What is our purpose and how do we forge, challenge, or resist it? What animates and gives dimension to our desires, dreams, and determination to exact what we think we want by any means necessary? To what lengths would we go to be happy, safe, or satisfied with the shape of our lives and at what costs? Poetry helps us answer these questions. That means, for me, at the heart of every poem is a writer trying to reach for and grapple with a possible or temporary or difficult answer to these questions. Poetry, from this view, is not a “reliving” or “retelling” of events. It is not transcription, as Carl Phillips reminds us. It is transformation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2020-08-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason in October 2018, I wrote “Everyone’s got their own voice. I’m not European.” on the back of a handout that was also covered with sketches for typeface idea. I still do not know what I was responding to. I guess all of it really.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">Ocean Vuong shared on his Instagram story one poem that changed his life:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post-metaphor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/05/post-metaphor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post-metaphor" /><published>2020-08-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/05/post-metaphor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/05/post-metaphor.html">&lt;h3&gt;Post-metaphor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tendency to compare to things rather than ideas, processes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;teachers often analogizing: is it actually helpful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a typeface is not a metaphor&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="August 2020" /><summary type="html">Post-metaphor</summary></entry></feed>