<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-02T11:19:36-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Archive #2</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New sites</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/15/new-sites.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New sites" /><published>2019-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/15/new-sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/15/new-sites.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Website&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I learned how to use git and the static site generator Jekyll back in 2017, because I was bothered by the idea of having a pre-templated website. I ended up making a website that looked like a Squarespace site. This new site is an evolution of that.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I bunch of ideas came to me after napping multiple times, so I went with it instead of overthinking. I don’t really get to use my favorite fonts, so I implemented them in the titles. Gotta say it feels good to buy fonts. I couldn’t not buy Orientation. Feeling uncertain about using Beastly justified, but good thing it’s not a tattoo. As for the shapes, the reuleaux triangle (Projects) is a refinement of the square (Fragments : experiments, past snapshots) which is carved from the circle (Annotations : thoughts, observations, context).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Homesite&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SmbmeOgWsqE&quot;&gt;↗ Lizzo — Good As Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I moved to ✨Minneapolis✨ It feels nice and homey here, and life currently is fairly simple in a non-complacent way. I don’t take sunny days and pretty skies for granted as much. And folks are quite welcoming here. What is this supposed Minnesota nice? I sense an undercurrent of hard work and humbleness in this city. I also became aware of Lizzo since she started out here. She makes the most uplifting music I have heard since discovering Talking Heads.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Website</summary></entry></feed>